hey guys welcome to this functions video
let f of x equal
5x plus 3 and g of x equal 3x plus 5.
find f plus g of 3. so what does this
mean well you can think of that as f of
plus g of three so to do f of three we
take the f
function and we plug three in for the x
so it's going to be five times three
plus three plus g of three means we look
at the g
function and we plug in three four x so
this will be three
times three plus five now we can just
simplify each of these five times three
is fifteen
plus three and three times three is nine
plus the five
fifteen plus three is eighteen plus and
nine plus five is fourteen
eighteen plus fourteen equals 32 and
that's our answer to the question
f plus g of 3 is equal to 32. comment
below on what math problem you'd like me
to solve next i'll talk to you soon
bye